msccruises.com 2011-06-05

# MSC Cruises : Privacy Policy

Important information pursuant to article 13 of the Italian Privacy Code

(Law Decree 196, dated 30 June 2003)

Pursuant to article 13 of the Italian Privacy Code (Law Decree 196/2003), MSC Crociere S.p.A. (hereafter "MSC" for short) hereby provides the following important information on the subject of processing the personal data of users visiting the website [www.msccruises.com](http://www.msccruises.com/) (hereafter the "site" for short), also reachable via other internet domains (e.g. [www.msccrociere.it](http://www.msccrociere.it/)).

  * Data controller
  * Granting access to personal data
  * Data processing methods and purposes
  * Data processing purposes
  * Cookies
  * Data security
  * Suggestions and queries

## Data controller

The controller of any personal data provided while visiting the site is: 

MSC Crociere S.p.A.,   
Via Agostino Depretis 31, Naples (Italy),   
tel. +39-081-7942 111

## Granting access to personal data

In general, your visits to the site will remain completely anonymous, as you will not be asked to insert any personal data to access the information published. However, in order to access a number of further services (e.g. requesting a catalogue, registering for our newsletter, etc.) or to receive a reply to any queries made (e.g. information requests), you could be asked to provide some data or MSC could come into possession of same (e.g. your email address in the event of your sending MSC a message).

## Data processing methods and purposes

Any personal data freely communicated to MSC via the website or by any other means (e.g. email, telephone and/or fax) will be processed in compliance with the Italian Privacy Code and the relevant European Directives.   
Indeed, MSC's primary commitment is to guarantee and respect the privacy of its customers and, in general, of all visitors to the MSC website. In the event of not granting MSC access to your personal data or of not authorising the processing of same, MSC may find itself unable to provide the services and/or information requested. All data provided will be processed in an automatic, computerised and/or manual manner, for the time required to achieve the purposes for which they were collected.

## Data processing purposes

1\. Compulsory: in the event of your personal data being collected to fulfil obligations and provide services relating to a stipulated contract (e.g. enrolment in the MSC Club), you will be required to provide all necessary personal data (e.g. name, surname, place and date of birth, email, etc.), which will be processed with the aim of executing the relating contractual services. To this end, the Privacy Code does not require you to authorise the processing of your personal data. 

2\. Optional: whenever expressly authorised by you, your personal data will also be processed for the promotional purposes of MSC and/or other associate or controlled companies (e.g. to send newsletters by email), for market research and with the aim of improving our services and the contents of our website.

Your personal data will not be communicated to third parties, except whenever expressly authorised by you, whenever required to fulfil contractual obligations, whenever required by MSC to fulfil legal obligations or whenever otherwise expressly allowed by law. In any other case, your data will not be disclosed.   
The site's software, however, might acquire personal data whose transmission is implicit in the use of internet communication protocols. The collection of such data does not in itself enable user identification. However, by its very nature - through elaborations and associations with data held by third parties - this data might enable user identification.   
This data category includes IP addresses or domain names of the computers used to connect to the site, as well as other parameters relating to the operating system and the type of browser adopted by the user.   
This data is used for the sole purpose of collecting anonymous statistics on the use of the website, or to check that the site functions correctly. Said data may also be used to ascertain liability in the event of IT crimes against the site or perpetrated via the site. Except in the above cases, web data will not be stored for more than 7 days.

## Cookies

The site might also make use of cookies, for the exclusive purpose of providing a specific service requested by the user or of granting access to an area of the website that would otherwise be forbidden. In these cases alone, said data will be used – merely for the time required – to transmit the relevant information and/or provide the specific service requested by the user.   
In any case, most browsers allow users to block cookies or to inform the user whenever a cookie is required. Users may choose to avail of said options, however in this case they will not be able to make use of the specific services requested or to access specific areas of the website where such information is required.

## Data security

In order to avoid the loss of data, unlawful or incorrect usage of same and unauthorised access, MSC regularly checks and updates its physical, electronic and logical security measures. However, unfortunately MSC cannot guarantee the secure transmission of data via the internet. As a result, notwithstanding our utmost commitment to ensure security, MSC cannot guarantee and ensure the security of the information transmitted to us via the internet, also due to circumstances and systems outside our control. Therefore, data is transmitted at your own risk, on the understanding that, once transmission is complete, MSC accepts all responsibility as regards security. The site might contain links to other internet sites deemed useful for users or relating to third party advertising. These resources might operate under the control of third parties, adopting different privacy policies. Therefore, MSC asks that you check the privacy policies of said third parties, as MSC has no control over any information provided by them.

The use of our website implies your acceptance of the present privacy policy. MSC reserves the right to amend or update this informative report at any time. Users are kindly requested to reread this report from time to time, in order to keep constantly updated on its contents.

## Suggestions and queries

MSC would be delighted to receive any query or suggestion regarding our privacy policy at [cruiseinfo@msccrociere.it](mailto:cruiseinfo@msccrociere.it)
